rheumatology.org 2014-04-23

# Policy on Privacy | American College of Rheumatology | ACR

Policy on Linking | Web Site Proprietary Legend and Disclaimer

This privacy statement covers the College's website www.rheumatology.org (website). The College is committed to our users' privacy, and therefore it has agreed to disclose its information and privacy practices. These practices are reviewed by outside sources, including legal representation and third parties such as TRUSTe.

This statement covers the following areas: 

  1. What personally identifiable information the College may collect
  2. What personally identifiable information third parties may collect through the website
  3. What organization may collect the information
  4. How the College may use the information
  5. With whom the College may share user information
  6. What choices are available to users regarding collection, use and distribution of the information
  7. What types of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under the College's control 
  8. How users can correct any inaccuracies in the information  

**If users have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact the College by e-mail at**

**Information Collection and Use**  
 **Information Collection**  
The College is the sole owner of any information collected on www.rheumatology.org. The College may collect information from our users at several different points on our website.

**Registration**  
In order to use this website, some users may be asked to complete a registration form. A user is required to give certain contact information (such as name, password, and e-mail address) during the registration process. We use some information for access to our site, and may use this information to contact the user about services on our site for which the user has expressed interest. The provision of other information is optional (such as address) but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site. None of this information is sold to or shared with third parties, and remains the sole property of the College.

**Order Information**  
The College requests information from the user on our order form. A user must provide contact information (such as name, e-mail, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill customer's orders. If we have trouble processing an order, the information is used to contact the user.

**Information Use**

**Profile**  
The College may store information that it collects through cookies, log files, clear gifs. A profile is stored information kept on individual users detailing their viewing preferences. Consequently, collected information is tied to the users' personally identifiable information to improve the content of the site for the user. This profile is used to tailor a user's visit to our site. The College does not share your profile with other third parties.

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's computer tied to information about the user. The College may use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. For the session ID cookie, once users close the browser, the cookie simply terminates. A persistent cookie is a small text file stored on the user's hard drive for an extended period of time. Persistent cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. 

By setting a cookie on the College's site, users would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on the site. If users reject the cookie, they may still use the College's site. The only drawback to this is that the user will be limited in some areas of the site s site. For example, the user will not be able to access the members' only section. See the "Profile" section.

**Log Files**  
Like most standard website servers, the College uses log files. This includes internet protocol addresses, browser type, internet service provider, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses, etc. are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

**Communications from the Site**  
 **Special Offers and Updates**  
The College may send all new members/users a welcoming e-mail to verify password and username. Established members will occasionally receive information onthe College's activities, products, services, special deals, and other information the College may deam of interest. Out of respect for the privacy, users have present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see the Choice and Opt-out sections.

**Service Announcements**  
On rare occasions it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement, e.g., if service is temporarily suspended for maintenance. Generally, users may not opt-out of these communications, though they can deactivate their account. However, these communications are not promotional in nature. Please see our Choice and Opt-out section.

**Customer Service**  
The College communicates with users on a regular basis to provide requested services and replies via e-mail or phone, in accordance with the user's wishes.

**Sharing**  
 **Legal Disclaimer**  
Though the College makes every effort to preserve user privacy, it may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein the College has a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on the website.

**Aggregate Information** (non-personally identifiable)  
The College occasionally shares non-personally identifiable aggregated demographic information with third parties.

**Personal Information**  
The College DOES NOT share personal information collected from this website with third parties.

**Service Providers**  
The College uses certain third-party providers as needed to conduct business and to provide specific services. For example, we use third party companies for certain meeting registration functions, abstract processing, market research, fundraising, journal publishing, shipping and credit card processing. We may share names, address information, phone, fax, and/or an e-mail address as necessary for the third party to provide these services. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services. We make our privacy policies clear to any providers, and adherence to these policies may be required for maintaining a business relationship with the College. These companies are under contractual obligation with the College, and do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes.

**Choice/Opt-out**  
Users are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having their information used for purposes not directly related to our site at the point where we ask for information. Users who do not wish to have us use their fax or e-mail addresses may opt-out of receiving these communications by e-mailing us at calling us at( 404) 633-3777 or mailing us at the address below.   
An opt-out mechanism is also offered on all blast e-mails from the College, and in the My Profile section of this website. 

**Links**  
This website contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we, the College is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. Users are encouraged to be aware when they leave the College's site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website. 

**Security**  
This website takes reasonable precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the web site, their information is protected both online and off-line.

Sensitive information such as credit card numbers are encrypted and protected with strong encryption software - SSL. Encryption means the credit card number is scrambled so that it is virtually impossible to be decoded and read by a hacker or other un-intended party. While on a secure page, such as our order form, the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer becomes locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when users are using an un-encrypted page. 

While the College uses SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, it also takes reasonable precautions to protect user-information off-line. All users' information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted in the College's offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our customer service representatives) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are in a secure environment. If users have any questions about the security please send an e-mail to

**Correcting/Updating/Deleting/Deactivating Personal Information**  
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as zip code, phone, e-mail or postal address), or if a user no longer desires our service, the College provides a way to correct, update or delete/deactivate users' personally identifiable information. This can be done at by e-mailing the Membership Department at or by contacting the College by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

**Notification of Changes**  
If the College decides to change the privacy policy, those changes will be posted to the homepage, and other places deemed appropriate so users are always aware of what information is collected, how it is used, and under what circumstances, if any, it is disclosed. The College will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected. 

If, however, the College is going to use users' personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection users will be notified via e-mail. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. However, if users have opted out of all communication with the site, or deleted/deactivated their account, then they will not be contacted, nor will their personal information be used in this new manner. In addition, if the College makes any material changes in the privacy practices that do not affect user information already stored in the database, the Collegewill post a prominent notice on our website notifying users of the change. In some cases where a notice is posted the College will also e-mail users, who have opted to receive communications from us, notifying them of the changes in privacy practices.

**Contact Information**  
If users have any questions or suggestions regarding this privacy policy, please contact the College.  
American College of Rheumatology; 2200 Lake Boulevard NE; Atlanta, GA 30319; USA; phone (404) 633-3777.
